Guide to the Arthur Kopit Papers MSS.141
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Magazines, Newspapers and Other Media
  - Video Tapes Box 4, 31142050718769 (Box 89)
    All tapes are VHS unless otherwise noted; includes both published copies and homemade recordings/dups.
    2 unlabeled tapes, Scotch UCA60 U-matic
    "Lewis and Clark--Kopit's tape" Scotch UCA60 U-matic
    "Marlene NTSC"
    "'Morocco' (1930) von Sternberg, Dietrich, Cooper"
    "'A Foreign Affair' (1948) Billy Wilder, Dietrich"
    "Cabaret"
    "Marlene Maria Riva Primetime 2-4-93"
    "Dietrich's jewelry"
    "M.D. in Berlin '60"
    "The Blue Angel"
    "Marlene, a film by Maximilian Schell"
    "Just a Gigolo"
    These materials were added in from the series marked "Miscellaneous".
    "Children at Risk"
    "True/Not True: When Memories can Be Trusted"
    "Multiple Personalities: The Search for Deadly Memories"
    "American Justice--'Satan, Rituals and Abuse"
    "CNN 3/3/94 Cruel Memory"
    "By Satan Possessed (HBO)"
    "Discovery Channel-Nikolai Tesla"
    "'The Faerie Queen' dir. by David Pountney"
    "Discovery Channel: Invention" 3 volumes
    "The Land of Far Away..."
    "legend"
    "The Monuments of Mars"
  - Computer Disks Box 1, 31142050718777 (Box 90)
    All computer media in this box are 5 inch floppy disks with numerous disks grouped in labeled plastic cases. They are listed here by case and number of disks. Indications of original applications and programs are usually noted on the disks with printouts of system information and file structure included in each case.
    "Phantom 1 disk; Bone-the-Fish 2 disks 11-19-89" 3 disks
    "Marlo Thomas, 'Deception' Drafts 1, 2, and 3 (Jan '89); 'Till Death Us Do Part" 7 disks
    "FastBack Plus Box #4...Total backup--verify on D: drive and C: drive" 17 disks
    "Pimpernel, Pimp draft 2; B-T-Fish; Printer files; Speller files; PTR-Maas; Bugliosi" 7 disks
    "Phantom Draft 2 7/6/89"3 disks
    "Roswell + Dreamhouse" 2 disks
    "Treasure Island...Draft 1 (but not the cut down version...Xywrite III" 5 disks
    "Treasure Island" 6 disks
    "Animal Hospital" 3 disks
    "Wings" 2 disks
    "Dreamhouse" 1 disk
    "Poet" Draft 2" dated 1991, first mention of this work in archive, 3 disks
    "Poet (Draft 2); Norman in Wonderland" 4 disks
    "Animal Hospital" 5 disks
    "Roswell Drafts 1, 8, 10" 8 disks
    1 empty blue case
    "Tom Swift Musical; Norman in Wonderland; Deception; Wonderland (Scientific Process)" 5 disks, first mention of "Tom Swift" yet that name not repeated on individual disk labels.
    "Archive backup Peter Maas Draft II 7/5/89" 4 disks
    "Feb '96 archive files...Soap (both drafts" 1 disk
    "Roswell" 9 disks
    "Gil Perlroth; 'Customiz' (an odd file), 'The Poet' Draft 1" 6 disks
    "Various disks; 'Tricks of the Trade'; 'Hands of a Stranger'; Audrey Cooper project; Gelber disk" 8 disks
    Unlabeled box containing labeled disks of "Roswell", Audrey Cooper project, and various applications; 10 disks
    "Fastback Plus full backup verify on" 16 disks
    "D: drive--C: drive Box #1" 19 disks
    "Archive files Gil Perlroth (musical); Phantom (film)...; Phantom (the musical)" 6 disks
    "Bone-the-Fish; Arcata; Phantom" 7 disks
    "Bone-the-Fish; Arcata; Phantom (film)" 7 disks
  - Computer Disks Box 2, 31142050718785 (Box 91)
    The following computer media in this box are 5 inch floppy disks with numerous disks grouped in plastic cases. They are listed here by case and number of disks. Indications of original applications and programs are usually noted on the disks with printouts of system information and file structure included in many cases.
    "Jamaica Kincaid tapes 8/20/90" 2 microcassettes in env.
    One large plastic filing tray of floppy diskettes containing 48 diskettes with the following material: "CRC by Nashua" (probable application); "Wings"; "Dreamhouse"; "Kopit"; numerous disks of the various Phantom incarnations; "Bone-the-Fish"; "The Poet"; "Peter Maas, 'The Legacy'"; "Nirvana"; "The Shroud"; "Till Death Us Do Part"; "Deception"; "Scarlet Pimpernel"; "Correspondence + misc."; "Discovery of America"; disks labeled "Play Padding" and "Plays #1 Perlroth"; along with two or so disks that are unlabeled or with obliterated labels.
    Other containers:
    "leslie--Backup disks June '92" 4 disks
    Unlabeled box of 3 disks; individual disk labels suggest this and the proceeding box contain personal material of Kopit and his family.
    Unlabeled box of 4 disks, apparently computer applications
    Group of 9 loose disks: "Kat", "Duras", "XyWrite III", Vassar Disk" #s 3 and 5, "B-T-Fish transfer", "Leslie Kincaid", "....Alex's BAS programs", "delta"
    "Leslie Disks sep '93" 4 disks
    "Leslie's Novel (the willows)" 10 disks
    "Backup LG novel" 3 disks
    "Amherst" 1 disk
    "LG: Diane Keaton" 1 disk
    "LG: Duras" 1 disk
    "LG: Novel Uncle Wiggily" 1 disk
    Unlabeled box containing "The Shroud" as well as disks of material relating to Leslie, Ben, Alex, and other material. 11 disks
    Unlabelled box containing disks mostly labeled "Kat", 6 disks
    Unlabeled box containing Leslie Garis work, mainly interviews and materials relating to articles on Joan Didion, Dominick Dunne, Jamaica Kincaid (see also audio tapes in this box), and Calvin Trillin. 17 disks
    "Tricks of the Trade" 9 disks, apparently all applications and utilities
    unlabeled box of LG materials, 7 disks
    "LG backup" 4 disks
    "Alex backup disk" 2 disks
    "Jamaica Kincaid" 1 disk
    "Amdek disks" 10 disks
    "Garis 6/93" 4 disks
    "Inverlochy Castle" 1 disk
    "LG: Susan Cheever" 1 disk
    "Susan Sontag" 1 disk
    The following media are 3 inch diskettes:
    "DOS 6 disks and some Leslie backup stuff" 3 disks
    "Novel Part II plus journal" 1 disk
    "Leslie Garis Novel Oct '93" 2 disks
    "Leslie #1 Novel part one" 1 disk
    Group of loose disks: "Kat's fifth grade work", "Ben's 7th grade work", "Alex-Dartmouth" (2 disks), "Backup of Leslie's novel".
  - Computer Disks Box 3, 31142050718793 (Box 92)
    "Xywrite\plays\Phantom\Paris\"\films\Phantom\Archive" 12 disks
    "Bugliosi, Peter Maas, Phantom, Deception" 9 disks
    "Bone-the-Fish" 7 disks
    "Peter Maas + files for scripts" 8 disks
    "Phantom (film) Arcata + LA" 14 disks
    "Storage Wings, Bugliosi" 13 disks
    "Deception" 3 disks
    "Peter Maas" 3 disks
    "Phantom--Paris" 3 disks
    "Tricks of the Trade; The Byte of Love"9 disks
    "Arcata Project" 2 disks
    "'Hasten the Bullet'; Perlroth 'My Place or Yours?'; Marlo Thomas" and other materials, 13 disks
    "Archive...Peter Maas" 4 disks
    "Multimate files" 8 disks
    Unlabeled box of applications, 6 disks
    "Phantom" 5 disks
    "Phantom" 2 disks
    unlabeled box of LG interviews, 5 disks
    unlabeled box of "Phantom" and applications
    "'Nirvana'; 'Bone-the-Fish'" 16 disks
    "to be reformatted and reused" 5 disks, unlabeled
    unlabeled box of "Phantom", "Bugliosi", "Idea for Plays" and other materials, 11 disks
    "DOS 2.0 and various Ericsson disks" 8 disks
    unlabeled box of system material and programs, 14 disks
  - Computer Disks Box 4, 31142050718801 (Box 93)
    Binders and manuals for DOS, XyWrite, etc. One binder of disks, one large tray of disks and one small case. All computer media in this box are 5 inch floppy disks.
    In Binder:
    Disks include 'Phantom' ca. 1985, letters, Audrey Cooper proposal, operating system, games, and program backup disks
    In small case:
    XyWrite program backup disks, 13 disks
    In tray:
    Program disks, games, instructional disks and the like, 62 disks
  - Jamaica Kincaid Interview, 1990-08-20; cuid22075; 2 audiocassettes (Box Digitized Access Files, File mss141_cuid22075A, mss141_cuid22075B, Box 91, Cassette cuid22075A, cuid22075B)
    Scope and Contents
    Leslie Garis interviews Jamaica Kincaid. Parts of the interview are quoted in a New York Times article written by Garis called "Through West Indian Eyes."
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: Microcassette, Qty.: 2, Total Duration: 120 min.
- Series III: Business Records
  This series is composed of numerous distinct groups of files apparently organized and accumulated at different times over three or four decades. The contents of each group are similar as records relating to personal and family finances are mixed in with materials relating to various works and productions. Among the personal materials are significant amounts of receipts, expenditure records, checking account and other bank statements, records relating to home maintenance, automobiles, mortgages, and income taxes. There is a significant body of records relating to the separate trusts Kopit established for each of his children and the investment records and taxes on them over the last two decades.
  Among the work-related records are significant amounts of correspondence and contracts recording the legal details and royalty payments of foreign and regional productions of his stage plays and publications of them in numerous countries. There are records relating Kopit's work in the television and film industry as well as some records relating the development of specific works. In particular, in this series is the only significant material relating to a small one-act play entitled "Elegy for the House that Ruth Built" that Kopit wrote to include in "Hitting for the Cycle" a production of numerous short plays about baseball, ca. 1996.
  - Business Files Box 1, ca. 1960s; 31142050718819 (Box 94)
    Two series of hanging files labeled A-Z, many with labeled Manila folders inside and all appartently from the later 1960s. Archival folders indicate most specific label present. Materials include notes and correspondence on various minor projects and proposals, personal material including correspondence, real estate materials, records relating to the birth of at least Kopit's first child; business correspondence concerning royalties and publications, drafts, notes, reviews and other material in various works ("Fresh Game", "Indians", "Sensuous Woman", "The Fox", "The Frog").
  - Business Files Box 2, 1996-1997; 31142050718827 (Box 95)
    A series of labeled hanging files (in alphabetical order by label) with multiple Manila folders in each. The Manila folders have been retained until their labels can be fully transcribed or photocopied, the hanging files' labels are transcribed on the archival folders. Materials, all apparently from the later 1990s, include financial records of credit cards, banks, attorneys, memberships, receipts, health insurance, and other material.
  - Business Files Box 3, ca. 1997; 31142050718835 (Box 96)
    A continuation of the previous box including records of investments, home insurance, home maintenance, and document's relating to family medical treatment. Following the folders labeled "Automobiles" and "Automobiles Insurance" a new group of files begin. These are mostly composed of folded pages removed from large financial ledgers used to record checks as well as bank statements for the checking accounts, cancelled checks and other receipts from 1997. Also included are large groups of unsorted receipts of all types, computer disks of tax and financial records.
    3" diskettes:
    "Taxes '92", "Taxes- '93", "Easy Boot"
    "Quicken 92-97" 6 disks in plastic case.
  - Business Files Box 4, 1995-1997; 31142050718843 (Box 97)
    Continues ledger and checking records from previous box.The ledgers begin in January of 1997 in the last box and continue until August or September here. A group of files are labeled as "Income 1997" and contain royalty receipts from miscellaneous plays, and from specific plays including "Wings", "Nirvana", "Phantom" and others. This box also contains a gigantic mass of unsorted receipts, statements, invoices and other documents; they have been foldered in the order found.
    Note: Box includes heavily annotated wall calendar from 1997 moved to Flat Box 14.
  - Business Files Box 5, ca. early 1990s; 31142050718850 (Box 98)
    Series of hanging files, many with numerous Manila folders as above. These files all pertain to specific works and productions. Records include contracts, correspondence, reviews, permissions, information on regional and international productions, including proposals for musicals based on "Wings". Productions documented include "Phantom", "Wings", "Success" (a one act play), "Legacy of a Mother's Murder" ("In a Child's Name"), "Dreamhouse", "Norman in Wonderland", "Hands of a Stranger", "The Poet", and "Roswell".
    "Wings" tape of musical adaptation by Jeffrey Lunden.
    "Andrew Rudin: Excerpts from..."
    Note: Oversized material, "Phantom" contracts moved to Flat Box 14
  - Business Files Box 6, 1976-ca. later 1990s; 31142050718868 (Box 99)
    Royalty checks and statements, investment statements, mostly of investments on behalf of Kopit's children, income tax forms for Kopit and members of his family. A second group of files were removed from labeled hanging files. The files are mostly assorted project material such as reviews, research, correspondence, etc., in no apparent order but also include materials on computers, office supplies and the like. Projects include "Blue Angel", "Wings", and an untitled project with Audrey Cooper.
    Note: One large folder of material on home appraisal and mortgage, one folder of trust agreements, two award plaques moved to Flat Box 14.
  - Business Files Box 7, ca. 1970s-1980s; 31142050718876 (Box 100)
    Continues files from previous box. Projects documented include Kopit's work at Austin Peay State University, "End of the World", "Wings" and "Dreamhouse." A separate set of files begins in this box apparently all from 1997 and 1998. These files begin with heaps of receipts for items such as travel, entertainment, and supplies; and family tax returns. Also included are records of "Elegy for the House that Ruth Built" a short one act play Kopit wrote to include in "Hitting for the Cycle" a production of numerous short plays about baseball, ca. 1996.Other files document publications and productions (mostly foreign and regional) of "Nine", "Sweet Smell of Success", "Phantom", "Road to Nirvana ", "Oh Dad, Poor Dad...", and "Indians". There are also records dealing with both the Writers' Guild and the Dramatist Guild.
  - Business Files Box 8, ca. 1980-1998; 31142050718884 (Box 101)
    Various business files in no apparent order including files on the family pets, the Writers' Guild health insurance and pension information, utility bills, documentation of the trusts for Kopit's children. Another group of records begins here with numerous files devoted to various productions including "Wings" (ca. 1978 and 1979), The files include personal and business correspondence, royalty documents, reviews and programs and other materials.
    "All Things Considered"
    "Jeffrey Nance..." 1 tape in envelope.
  - Business Files Box 9, ca. early 1970s-mid 1990s; 31142050718892 (Box 102)
    A continuation of files from the previous box. Files on various projects including "Lewis and Clark", Starstruck" and "Wings". Other materials include original playbill and publicity photos of "Oh Dad, Poor Dad", notes on other works, teleplays of "Sparrow" by Domenico Sabatini, and a treatment for a screenplay by Kopit entitled "The Winner", undated. After the folders on Wings, a new set of records begins dated ca. 1976.These include some personal materials but also records of "Lewis and Clark" (significant correspondence) and "Discovery of America", and "Secrets of the Rich" (handwritten and typescript drafts). These project records are followed by travel expense records, personal bills, and other materials from ca. 1994-95.
    "Starstruck?"
    "'Oh Dad, Poor Dad' Lyrics and Music by Elsa Whyte" 45 phonograph.
    Note: Folder of "Oh Dad" at front of box contains original publicity photos, playbill and phonograph.
  - Business Files Box 10, ca. 1975-1990; 31142050718900 (Box 103)
    First folders continue assorted personal bills and records from previous box, ca. 1994-95. Following those two folders is a new set of records found in an unlabeled series (original series III) and dated ca. 1975-85. These files comprise assorted personal material such as club memberships, recipes, property information, etc. These are followed by project materials including a large amount of original correspondence between Ken, Everett and Jean Taylor, figures in legal case upon which "In a Child's Name" (aka "Legacy of a Mother's Murder") was based; a manuscript of the story written by Al Benigno, a detective (or attorney), index cards for "Discovery of America", and assorted material for "Good Help is Hard to Find"
  - Business Files Box 11, 1969-1992; 31142050718918 (Box 104)
    Miscellaneous business materials found in different locations. The files include monthly datebooks from 19990, checkbook registers from mid to late 1980s, canceled checks from 1988, miscellaneous news clippings, materials on "Animal Hospital", and some materials relating to Kopit's work at CCNY. There is a set of materials related to "Theater Perspectives" by Audrey Cooper, a documentary project for public television, ca. 1988. Also included are various home records from ca. 1990; receipts and a datebook from 1969-1971, computer printouts of checking account debits and credits, ca. 1992. Finally, there is a small amount of records concerning Kopit's participation (1988?) in the Collaborative Play Project, apparently an annual workshop in California and a significant collection of articles, research, audio tapes, and drafts of a piece Kopit wrote on producer Roger L. Stevens for a Kennedy Center Honors program in 1988.
    micro cassettes in envelope
    "Bob Whitehead"
    "Conversations with Roger Stevens" 2 tapes
    "Leonard Bernstein"
    "Arthur Schlessinger Jr."
  - Business Files Box 12, ca. 1993-1996; 31142050718926 (Box 105)
    Miscellaneous material found elsewhere in the collection. Includes memos and documents from CCNY, an Italian translation of "Wings", synopsis and full script of "Salvage" by Mary Beth Becker, and materials sent to Kopit for possible film adaptation.
    Nancy Taylor Rosenberg, Interest of Justice (Dutton: New York, 1993)
    Published information package and VHS tape by Communications Control Systems, a surveillance manufacturer.
  - Business Files Box 12, 1965-1969; 31142050718934 (Box 106)
    Early business materials found among personal papers and correspondence. Material includes cancelled checks from 1965; cancelled checks belonging to his parents 1965-1968; bills for 1965 and 1967 including mailed monthly tabs from Elaine's, Sardi's, the Harvard club, credit card statements, etc.; a large volume of news clippings, ca. 1969.
    Note: One legal folder of material, all royalty statements from 1969 moved to Flat Box 14.
  - Business Files Box 13, ca. 1980-1995; 31142050718942 (Box 107)
    Business files found elsewhere in the collection and moved. These materials are from hanging files, all apparently from the 1980s, and consist of home improvement records, personal and business correspondence, some personal financial materials and other materials. A second set of records deal largely with the Dramatists' Guild, all materials from the 1990s, and includes a large amount of correspondence regarding various productions and Guild business, newsletters and Guild publications and materials regarding the Tony Awards, playbills and other miscellaneous materials from the period.
    Note: One oversized legal folder of Tony Award material moved to Flat Box 15.
  - Business Files Box 14, 31142050718959 (Box 108)
    These materials have been left in their original hanging files. The materials largely deal with specific projects, including Jekyll and Hyde, "End of the World", "Ropongo" and "Discovery of America" and include scripts and script revisions. There is also material on other topics and some correspondence.
- Series IV: Personal Materials
  Personal materials in the Kopit collection fall into typical types of records. There is a significant amount of ephemera including high school yearbooks and newspapers, scrapbooks from the 1960" that chart the success of Kopit's plays, their influence on theater and on cultured society of New York, and Kopit's rise in the same community. There is an additional large amount of newspaper reviews, clippings and advertisements saved by Kopit and his family or forwarded to them by Audrey Wood, Kopit's agent, or by friends and professional acquaintances.
  A large amount of documentation exists here on Kopit's years at Harvard from which he graduated in 1959. These include papers, exam books and notebooks. Extensive correspondence between Kopit and his parents and friends, and drafts and copies of scripts Kopit wrote while at Harvard including "Oh Dad, Poor Dad...", "Sing to Me Through Open Windows", "The Questioning of Nick" and "The Death of Houdini." The correspondence details the development and staging of these works at Harvard and the collection includes ticket stubs, stage bills reviews and notices of them. The personal files also yield records on Kopit's activity following his graduation, when he traveled in Europe, and leading up to and beyond the Broadway Premiere of "Oh Dad, Poor Dad...". The files provide a sketchier picture of Kopit's activities after the mid-1960s but help fill in details on the development and staging of "Indians", his marriage to Leslie Garis, and other activities.
  Many materials here including correspondence appear to have been in the possession of Kopit's parents, George and Maxine. Mixed in then with materials relating to Arthur are correspondence between Gorge and Maxine Kopit and others, business records, bills and other materials for the elder Kopit's, and records of Arthur's career clearly collected by the parents. There is a large amount of photographs, the greater portion of them from Kopit's childhood up until his first success, his parents, extended family and perhaps further ancestors. None are labeled. Two boxes of material created originating from Leslie Garis (journals, diaries, and extensive documentation of the writing of her unpublished novel) have been moved to the end of the collection.
  - Personal Materials Box 1, 1960-1964; 31142050718967 (Box 109)
    6 large scrapbooks, composed almost solely of clippings from newspapers and some magazines from the years 1960-1964. The clippings are typically of society columns, theater news, gossipy pieces, as well as reviews. One or two playbills inserted.
  - Personal Materials Box 2, 1960-1967; 31142050718975 (Box 110)
    Same as previous. 5 scrapbooks ranging from 1960-1967.
  - Personal Materials Box 3, ca. 1960-1967; 31142050718983 (Box 111)
    Same as previous. 5 scrapbooks
  - Personal Materials Box 4, ca. 1960-1975; 31142050718991 (Box 112)
    3 scrapbooks ranging from 1958-1962; leather portfolios of magazines and news clippings, correspondence, financial documents and many materials of Kopit's parents; 1967 correspondence between Kopit and his parent while in Spain; photographs including family pictures and set visits to the film of "Indians" and a portrait of Robert Altman, the director.
  - Personal Materials Box 5, 1953-1970; 31142050719007 (Box 113)